Guide to the Lindseth collection of American woman suffrage,[ca. 1820-1920].
Lindseth collection of American woman suffrage,[ca. 1820-1920]
- Series II. Manuscripts
  - Wiley, Anna Kelton; Connor, Elsa Van Vleet. Typed Mimeographed Letter to "Fellow Home-Maker." Washington, DC. Announces a nationwide demonstration on behalf of the federal suffrage amendment starting on May 2 and a national suffrage procession in Washington on May 9. Signed by the chairman and vice chairman of the Committee on Home-Makers Section. Letter is on Congressional Union for Woman Suffrage letterhead., March 24, 1914; S-262 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Series III. Pins & Ribbons
  - Pins & Ribbons: Souvenir ribbon of the N. Y. W. S. A. 26th Annual Convention. Ithaca, NY: New York State Woman Suffrage Association., 1894; S-471 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Pins & Ribbons: Illinois Equal Right Ribbon Badge., [c. 1906]; S-453 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Pins & Ribbons: "Votes for women" pin. Chicago: Amalgamated Lithographers of America., [c. 1915-1917]; S-448 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Pins & Ribbons: Housewives League Pin. Rochester, NY: Bastian Bros. Co., [1910]; S-435 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pins & Ribbons: "Grand G.O.P. Parade"., November 17, 1894; S-433 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Pins & Ribbons: Massachusetts Woman's Suffrage Association Pin, "Yes". Boston: Massachusetts Woman's Suffrage Association., [c. 1910]; S-428 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Pins & Ribbons: Women Suffrage "Citizen - 1915" pin. Newark, NJ: Whitehead & Hoag Co., 1915; S-429 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Pins & Ribbons: "Votes for women Indiana" Pinback., 1917-1919; S-382 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Pins & Ribbons: "Votes for women" pin. [NY: Woman Suffrage Pub. Co., Inc., [c. 1917]; S-217 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Pins & Ribbons: "Vote NO on Woman Suffrage" pin., [c. 1915]; S-339 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Pins & Ribbons: "Equal Suffrage" pinback. Rochester, NY: Bastian Bros. Co., [1915]; S-341 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Pins & Ribbons: "Votes for Women, Penna. 1915" pinback. [Newark, NJ: Whitehead & Hoag Co.]., 1915; S-360 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Graphics
  - Kent, J. H. Signed Photograph of Susan B. Anthony. Rochester, NY., 1901; S-166 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hurn, J. W. Carte de Visite of Susan B. Anthony and Elizabeth Cady Stanton. Philadelphia., [c. 1870]; S-383 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - National Association of Woman Suffrage. Suffrage Souvenir with Photographs of Susan B. Anthony and Anna Howard Shaw. N.P., 1903; S-485 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Anon. Postcard with Photograph of Inez Milholland. Washington, DC: Leet Bros. Photograph of Inez Milholland on horseback, dressed as a medieval herald, heading the suffrage parade on March 3, 1913. Caption reads "Miss Inez Milholland, Herald.", 1913; S-155 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Anon. Signed Photograph of E. Sylvia Pankhurst. London. Autograph inscription reads "E. Sylvia Pankhurst-15 imprisonments." Image is reproduced in E. Sylvia Pankhurst: Portrait of a Radical (1987) by Patricia W. Romero., 1925; S-250 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Anon. Stereoview of Anna Howard Shaw. Chicago, London: Keystone View Co. Brief biography printed on the back under the heading "Dr. Anna Howard Shaw, Suffrage Leader.", [c. 1900]; S-135 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Anon. Signed Photograph of Elizabeth Cady Stanton. Philadelphia: Frey., 1875; S-371 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Anon. Carte de Visite of Elizabeth Cady Stanton. New York: Frey., [c. 1870]; S-125 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hurn, J. W. Carte de Visite of Lucy Stone, Mary Livermore, and Wendell Phillips. Philadelphia., [c. 1868]; S-085 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Anon. Stereoview of Suffragette Parade. Chicago, London: Keystone View Co. Caption reads "Suffragette Parade-- G. Marshal, Mrs. Richard Burleson; Herald, Miss Inez Milholland; and other Prominent Workers on Horseback--March 3, 1913, Washington, D.C." Text on the back under the heading "A Suffrage Parade.", March 13, 1913; S-221 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Stalee, W. H. Photograph of Suffrage March. Washington, DC., April 1913; S-067 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - National Women's Social and Political Union; Smith, Lizzie Caswall. Postcard with Photograph of Christabel Pankhurst. London: Sandle Brothers., [c. 1910]; S-440 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Anon. Postcard with Photograph of Emmeline Pankhurst and Elizabeth Wolstenholme Elmy at Hyde Park Demonstration. London: Sandle Brothers. Caption reads "Hyde Park Demonstration, Sunday, June 21, 1908: Mrs. Pankhurst, Mrs. Wolstenholme Elmy.", 1908; S-441 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Anon. Postcard with Photograph of Suffrage Parade in Washington, DC. Baltimore: I and M. Ottenheimer. Caption reads "Liberty and Her Attendants- (Suffragettes Tableau) in Front of Treasury Bldg. March 3-1913-Washington D.C.", March 3, 1913; S-427 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Anon. Postcard with Photograph of Emmeline Pankhurst. London: Photochrom Co. Caption reads "Mrs. Pankhurst Arrested in Victoria Street. Feb. 13, 1908." Postcard sender mentions attending a suffrage meeting., February 13, 1908; S-354 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - National Women's Social and Political Union; Jacolette, Martin. Postcard with Photograph of Emmeline Pankhurst. England., 1909; S-352 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Anon. News Service Photograph of Woman Suffrage Parade in New York City. New York: Keystone View Co., 1915; S-362 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Leslie Woman Suffrage Commission. Signed Publicity Photograph of Elizabeth Cady Stanton. New York., [c.1915-1917]; S-363 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Anon. Signed Photograph of Carrie Chapman Catt. New Rochelle, NY., July 15, 1942; S-364 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Anon. Anti-suffrage Postcard with Photograph of a Group of Women, One on Horseback with "Suffragist" Sign. Greenwich, OH., [c. 1913-1914]; S-366 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Gilman, Charlotte Perkins: Set of 16 different trade cards for two brands of soap. Providence, RI; or, Boston, MA., [c. 1876-1880]; S-170 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - New York State Woman Suffrage Party: Woman suffrage pledge form. [NYC]: New York State Woman Suffrage Party., [1917]; S-209 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Woodhull, Victoria: Trade card showing Woodhull at the New York Stock Exchange. NY: Kerr & Company., [c. 1870]; S-023 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - World Woman's Party: Letterhead. Washington, DC: World Woman's Party., [1939, not before]; S-078 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Postcard: "Why not let mother vote?". Chicago., 1913; S-220 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Stamp: "Vote for the Woman Suffrage Amendment in November!" Suffrage stamp., 1915; S-307 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Postcard: "Oh! Where is my wandering wife to-night?". Holmfirth, England: Bamforth & Co., 1916; S-231 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Postcard: "My wife's joined the Suffrage Movement, (I've suffered ever since!). NY: Bamforth & Co., 1910; S-230 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Playing Card: "Votes for women"., [1900]; S-434 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Postcard: "Thanksgiving Day Greetings"., 1921; S-431 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Postcard: "The Suffragette"., 1913; S-432 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Phoenix Manufacturing Co.: Woman's suffrage stove polish advertisement. Taunton, MA: Phoenix Manufacturing Co., [c. 1900]; S-425 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - National American Woman Suffrage Association: Woman suffrage postcard. Grand Rapids, MI: Cargill Company., 1910; S-344 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - National American Woman Suffrage Association: Woman suffrage postcard. Grand Rapids, MI: Cargill Company., 1910; S-345 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - National American Woman Suffrage Association: Woman suffrage postcard. Grand Rapids, MI: Cargill Company., 1910; S-343 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Postcard: Suffragette postcard. London: C. W. Faulkner & Co., Ltd., 1913; S-351 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Banner: "Votes for women"., [c. 1910]; S-423 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Anon. Glass plate negative. "A suffragette parade". Meadville, PA: Keystone View Co., H228 (11940), [c. 1900]; Purchased by John Lindseth (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Series V. Bound Manuscripts
  - Harper, Frances Ellen Watkins [2 items with one number]: Autograph verse signed. Autograph card housed in red buckram clamshell. See Box 6 for actual verse. Philadelphia., [c. 1895]; S-054 (Folder Bd. Ms. 1)
  - Photograph album (4 photographs): Woman Suffrage Parade in New York City, May 4, 1912., May 4, 1912; S-438 (Folder Bd. Ms. 2)
  - Pins and Ribbons: Suffrage pinback and free silver, Populist and Republican party ballots from the 1893 Colorado referendum on woman suffrage., 1893; S-263 (Folder Bd. Ms. 3)
  - Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association: 1915 Pinback & ribbon: "Votes for Women" together with small pamphlet: "Woman Suffrage 1915", 1915; S-240 (Folder Bd. Ms. 4)
  - Dominy, Arthur: Autograph affidavit signed by Arthur Dominy relating to Margaret [Sarah] Fuller., 1901; S-056 (Folder Bd. Ms. 5)
  - Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association. Votes for Women Fan. Boston. Reads "Keep cool! There will be nothing to worry about after we get Votes for Women, Election Day, November 2." Reverse side includes map graphic and additional text., [c. 1916]; S-458 (Folder Bd. Ms. 6)
  - Lindseth, John. Lindseth Collection of Woman Suffrage: A Guide to the Collection. (Folder Bd. Ms. 7)
  - Women's Anti-Suffrage Association of Massachusetts. "Vote NO on Woman Suffrage". FAN., November 2, 1915; Purchase (Folder Bd. Ms. 8)
  - Brown, Harriet Connor (Editor): Official program of the Woman's Suffrage Procession, Washington, D.C., March 3, 1913; S-483 (Folder JF 851 .N27 1913 ++)
- Series VI. Artifacts
  - Bowker, Dorothy: Hunger strike medal. London: Women's Social & Political Union., 1912; S-430 (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B.: Susan B. Anthony citrus spoon; with The original advertisement from the 1891 Jewelers circular., 1891; S-336 (Box 14)
  - Hutschenreuther. Tea cup of white porcelain; lettered in gold, "Votes for Women". Selb, Bavaria: Hutschenreuther., [c. 1901]; S-381 (Box 14)
- Series VII. Videocassettes
  - Pollak, Ruth and Felicia Widmann: 'One woman, one vote' videocassette., 1996; S-070 (Box V-826)
- Series VIII. Additional Manuscript Materials
  - Anon. 4 woman suffrage 50th Anniversary postage stamps. 8 postcards: "Sisterhood is powerful"; "Standing up for women's rights"; "Put me among the girls"; "Votes for women"; "Beg pardon ..."; "Just home from college"; "Now madam ..."; "Wayrane church [sic]". (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Anon. 8 postcards: "I'll get that vote yet!!!"; "To my Valentine ..."; "My hero!"; "Great Salvage Sale"; "Bargains in men"; "Mummy's a suffragette"; "By gum! ..."; "Great suffrage demonstration". (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Anon. 8 postcards: "I say down with ..."; "Stand up for women's rights"; "Valentine's greetings ..."; "I want to speak for myself ..."; "When women get the vote"; "Oh, the darling!"; "Where women vote--By the new fire-side"; "Where women vote--It's turn about all round". (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Anon. 8 postcards: "Where women vote--My turn will come"; "Where women vote--Looking backward"; "Where women vote--A family tangle"; "Suffragette, who me?"; "The fox and the crow"; "When women vote"; "No taxation without representation"; "They have a cheek ..."., S-432 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Anon. 9 postcards: "Now! Where's my vote?"; "I want a vote"; "Once I get my liberty ..."; "The simple life"; "Miss Alison Neilans"; "This is what "Votes for Women" has done for me!"; "Miss Mary Gawthorpe"; "Miss Charlotte Marsh"; "Dame Christabel Pankhurst". (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Anon. Signed Photograph of Lillie Devereux Blake. N.P. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Anon. Carte de Visite of Virginia Woodhull. N.P., [c. 1870-1873] (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Briggs, May Brayton. Autograph Manuscript of Verse Entitled "Suffrage." Bradford, MA. Part of the suffrage archive of May Brayton Briggs. (A), [c. 1915-1917]; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Briggs, May Brayton. Autograph Manuscripts, Including Signed Manuscript Read at White Church. Bradford, MA. Quotes from "The Wage Earning Woman and the State" by Edith Abott and Sophonisba Breckinridge. Also quotes Sarah Platt Decket, Wendell Phillips, Woodrow Wilson, examples of Catholic opinions on woman suffrage, and a report in the Boston Sunday Post on a suffrage parade in Boston. Signed manuscript includes autograph notation "Written for, and read at, Thursday evening service at White Church Bradford Mass on request of Rev. Henry A. Arnold, then Pastor, following along the lines of subject of the evenings discussion Our soldiers now fighting in France." Part of the suffrage archive of May Brayton Briggs. (A), [c. 1915-1917]; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association. Invitation to a Woman Suffrage Meeting. Boston. Card. Part of the suffrage archive of May Brayton Briggs. (B), [c. 1915-1918]; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association. Ticket to a Public Meeting Under the Auspices of the Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association Featuring Patriotic Addresses by Anna Howard Shaw and Carrie Chapman Catt. Boston. Pencil notation on back of the ticket. Part of the suffrage archive of May Brayton Briggs. (C), 1918; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association; Woman's Journal; Blackwell, Alice Stone. Suffrage and Temperance: By Alice Stone Blackwell, Editor of the Woman's Journal. Boston. Leaflet. Part of the suffrage archive of May Brayton Briggs. (E), [c. 1914]; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association; Blackwell, Alice Stone. Woman Suffrage 1915. Boston. Pamphlet. Includes "The Progress of Woman Suffrage" by Alice Stone Blackwell, content signed by Gertrude Halladay Leonard and Teresa A. Crowley, suffrage endorsements, and illustrations by Howard Jones and John Quill. Part of the suffrage archive of May Brayton Briggs. (F), 1915; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - National Union of Women's Suffrage Societies; Harrison, Jane Ellen. "Homo Sum" Being a Letter to an Anti-Suffragist from an Anthropologist. By Jane E. Harrison, LL.D. 2nd Edition. London. Pamphlet. Includes a list of publications by the National Union of Women's Suffrage Societies. Part of the suffrage archive of May Brayton Briggs. (G), [c. 1908-1912]; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Equal Franchise Society of Pennsylvania; Phillips, Wendell. Shall Women Have the Right to Vote? Address by Wendell Phillips at Worcester, Mass. 1851. N.P. 1916. Pamphlet. Includes a forward signed S.Y.S. and an extract of George William Curtis' Eulogy on Wendell Phillips Before the Municipal Authorities of Boston, April 18, 1884. Part of the suffrage archive of May Brayton Briggs. (H), April 18, 1884; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Smith, Eliza. ALS. East Dennis, MA. Discusses her lectures and the upcoming convention in Sept., July 29, 1852; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Weston, Anne Warren. ALS to Mrs. Jonathan A. Allen. Boston. Letter is written on a pamphlet including the "Address of the Boston Female Anti-Slavery Society to the Women of New England" signed by Mary S. Parker and Maria Weston Chapman. Pamphlet also includes blank petition forms to the House of Representatives and the Senate for the abolition of slavery in the District of Columbia and of the slave trade in the U.S. and against the admission of Texas as a slave-holding territory., July 26m 1837; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Anon. Broadside: "Should Women Vote?" Manchester, England: TAECAN Publishing Co., Purchase (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - National Woman Suffrage Publishing Co. This Little Book Contains Every Reason Why Women Should Not Vote. New York. Pamphlet. Inside pages are blank., [c. 1917]; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Woman Suffrage Pledge Form--New York. NY State Woman Suffrage Party., [c. 1915-1917]; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Women's Loyal National League. Men's Emancipation Petition. Women's Emancipation Petition. New York. 2 sheets. Petitions to the U.S. Senate and House of Representatives for "an Act emancipating all persons of African descent held to involuntary service or labor in the United States." Men's Emancipation Petition lists Susan B. Anthony as addressee at the Women's Loyal National League., [c. 1863]; Purchase (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Argetsinger, Gerald S. "Equality of Rights: The First Woman's Rights Convention". An historic dramatization in celebration of the Sesquicentennial of 1848 Woman's Rights Convention, performed for the 1998 Celebration ..., 1998 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Anonymous. 3 photographs of students protesting female entry to universities in Cambridge, England. Cambridge, Eng.: [s.n.], Purchase (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Briggs, May Brayton. Autograph Manuscript Signed. Bradford, MA. Discusses an editorial and letters on feminism and equal suffrage in the Jan. 18 and Feb. 26 Congregationalist. Part of the suffrage archive of May Brayton Briggs. (A), [c. 1915]; Purchase (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Anon. Your Vote Should Help to Defeat John W. Weeks for the United States Senator at the Election November 5th. Boston. Handbill. Issued over the names John S. Codman, Henry D. Nunn, William Shaw, and Henry D. Sleeper. Part of the suffrage archive of May Brayton Briggs. (D), November 5, 1918; Purchase (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "Do we want the suffragette?" Pictorial Review. [S.l.]: Advertising poster printed in red and black., [1910]; Purchase (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Anon. Illustration with Title "Women's Suffrage-The National Demonstration at St. James's Hall." The Graphic. p. 516. Oversized. Illustration includes banner with text "Miss Rhoda Garrett.", May 22, 1880; Purchase (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Anon. Illustration with Title "Conference of the Women's Franchise League in Russell Square." The Graphic. p. 688. Oversized. Column "Women and the Franchise" on the reverse side, p. 687, describes the conference and mentions participants, including Emmeline Pankhurst and Harriot Stanton Blatch., December 12, 1891; Purchase (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Begg, S. Illustration with Title "Woman-A Person or Not a Person?" and Subtitle "A Girl-Graduate at the Bar of the House of Lords: Miss Crystal Macmillan Appealing for the Right to Vote." Illustrated London News. p. 711., November 21, 1908; Oversized (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Flere, H. H. Illustration with Title "The Right Argument: Which Is Fitter to Have a Vote?" and Subtitle "Where the Real Head of the House Has No Voice in the Country's Affairs." Illustrated London News. p. 119., January 25, 1908; Oversized. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Anon. Photograph of Miss Fitzherbert of the Women's Freedom League with Title "The Suffragettes' Dash for the Royal Carriage at the Opening of Parliament" and Subtitle "Stopped Within Four Yards of the King's Carriage: A Suffragette Removed by Policemen." Illustrated London News. p. 151., February 1, 1908; Oversized. Photograph by Illustrations Bureau. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - The Woman's Press. Memento of Women's Coronation Procession to demand Votes for Women: Order of March and Descriptive Program. Saturday, June 17, 1911. London: Woman's Press., 1911; Purchase (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Women's Freedom League. The Vote Blotter. London: "The Vote" Office; Women's Freedom League., Purchase (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Panko or Votes for Women Card Game. London: Peter Gurney. Game includes 8 suits of 6 cards, 4 pro-suffrage and 4 anti-suffrage. Illustrations by E. T. Reed include caricatures of Emmeline Pankhurst, Lord Herbert Asquith, and members of his cabinet, including Lloyd George and Winston Churchill., [c. 1913-1915] (Box 12)
  - Pank-a-Squith Suffrage Board Game. N.P. (Box 12)
  - Anon. Ms. Playing Cards. Lib Deck. N.P. Cards illustrated with a woman holding a "Votes for Women" sign., 1975 (Box 12)
  - National Woman's Party. Color Poster with Illustration of Inez Milholland Dressed as a Herald on Horseback and Text "Inez Milholland Boissevain Who Died for the Freedom of Women." N.P. Oversized, mounted., 1917; S-461 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Anon. Photograph of Women's Jubilee Dinner. London: Rawood. Oversized, mounted., May 14, 1935; S-356 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Anthony, Susan B. TLS. Rochester, NY. Oversized, in frame with photograph. Mentions Emeline S. Hicks., June 13, 1903; S-256 (Box 13, Folder 3)